Guide to the Stephen Sandy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2006 Acquisition, 1957-2006; 8; 4.21; (5 boxes)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Huang, Chi-Chung, 1986-2001, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - Hubbard, Sue, 2005, undated (Box 24)
    - Kernan, Michael, 2005 May 6 (Box 25)
    - Kolatch, Myron, 2005, undated (Box 25)
    - Lane, John, 1998-2002 (Box 25)
    - Lanyon, Ellen, 1999-2005 (Box 25)
    - Latuchie, Karen, 2003-2005 (Box 25)
    - Lea, Sydney, 2003-2004, undated (Box 25)
    - Leib, Jeffrey, 2000-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Lethem, Jonathan, 2003-2005 (Box 25)
    - Levis, Larry, 1983-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Lindley, Daniel & Lucia, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
    - Logan, Leroy, 1990 (Box 25)
    - Lopate, Phillip, undated (Box 25)
    - Louisiana State University Press, 1998-1999 (Box 25)
    - Lum, Wing Tek, 1998 February 11 (Box 25)
    - Lurie, Alison, 2002 (Box 25)
    - Malanga, Gerard, 2002-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Malinowitz, Evelyn, 2002, undated (Box 25)
    - Maris, Kathryn, 1999-2005 (Box 25)
    - Markowitz, Mitch, 1998-2004 (Box 25)
    - Marks, Corey, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Martin, Harold C., 1995-1999, undated (Box 25)
    - Massimilla, Stephen, 2002-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Mathews, Harry, 2002-2003 (Box 25)
    - Mayo, Tim, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
    - McCullough, Angus, 2006 (Box 25)
    - McFall, Gardner, 2003-2005 (Box 25)
    - McIver, Beverly, circa 1998-2003 (Box 25)
    - Merrill, James, 1978-1985 (Box 25)
    - Middleton, Polly, 2004-2006 (Box 25)
    - Mitten, David, 1984-2004 (Box 25)
    - Mogelson, Luke, 2002-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Morrison, Micah, 2002-2005 (Box 25)
    - Movius, Geoffrey, 2003-2004 (Box 25)
    - Movius, John, 2004-2005, undated (Box 25)
    - National Endowment of the Arts, 1988 (Box 25)
    - Nemerov, Howard, 1991 July 5 (Box 25)
    - New England Review, 1997 December 3 (Box 25)
    - The New Leader, 2005 (Box 25)
    - The New Yorker, 1966-2005, undated (Box 25)
    - Nunley, Richard, 1992-2003, undated (Box 25)
    - Oliver, Mary, 1996, undated (Box 25)
    - The Paris Review, 2002-2005 (Box 25)
    - Pettingell, Phoebe, 1988-2006 (Box 25)
    - Poetry, 2002-2004 (Box 25)
    - Poets House, 1996-2005 (Box 25)
    - Poirier, Mare, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Porter, David, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
    - Randall, Julia, 1994-2005, undated (Box 25)
    - The Reader, 2004-2005, undated (Box 25)
    - Reed, Mark, 1998-2005 (Box 25)
    - Reeve, Franklin, 2003-2004 (Box 25)
    - Ronk, Martha, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Rorem, Ned, 2002 (Box 26)
    - Rudman, Mark, 2003-2005 (Box 26)
    - Ruefle, Mary, 2002-2004, undated (Box 26)
    - Saltonstall, Stephen, 1994 November 30 (Box 26)
    - Salzman, Eva, 1999 April 26 (Box 26)
    - Sandy, Alan, 1957-2002; 2 (Box 26)
    - Schneebaum, Tobias, 2002-2003, undated (Box 26)
    - Share, Don, 2005, undated (Box 26)
    - Slavitt, David, 2005 (Box 26)
    - Souter, David, 2002-2005 (Box 26)
    - Spiegelman, Willard, 2002-2004 (Box 26)
    - St. Armand, Barton L., 1991-2006, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - Stern, Jerry, 1998-2004 (Box 26)
    - Stevenson, Anne, 1990-1991, undated (Box 26)
    - Svoboda, Teresa, 2002-2006 (Box 26)
    - Swenson, Karen, 2003-2005, undated (Box 26)
    - Takano, Masao, 1969-2005, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - Tin House, 2004 (Box 26)
    - Tokunaga, Shozo, 2002-2004 (Box 26)
    - Totten, Shay, 2004, undated (Box 26)
    - University of Pittsburgh Press, 2004, undated (Box 26)
    - Viscusi, Margo, 2002, undated (Box 26)
    - West Chester University Poetry Conference, 2006 (Box 26)
    - Western Humanities Review, 2005-2006 (Box 26)
    - Wilner, Eleanor, 2005 (Box 26)
    - Wilson, Richard, 2003, undated (Box 26)
    - Wroth, Kinvin, 1998 June 26 (Box 26)
    - Wylie, Andrew, 1967 February 11 (Box 26)
    - Yale College, Phi Beta Kappa, 2003, undated (Box 26)
    - Family, 1965-1966; 2 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence: Japan, 1967-1969; 2 (Box 26)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1963-2006; 3 (Box 26)
  - Writings
    - "Above Como", undated (Box 27)
    - A Cloak for Hercules; translated by Stephen Sandy, undated (Box 27)
    - Drafts, undated; 9 (Box 27)
    - Graduation talk, Bennington College, 2003 (Box 27)
    - "Manifestations", undated (Box 27)
    - Riding to Greylock, 1983, undated (Box 27)
    - "Shooting Sensation", undated (Box 27)
    - Surface Impressions, 2001-2002, undated; 4 (Box 27)
    - "To a Martis", undated (Box 27)
    - "Tenants", undated (Box 27)
    - Maxwings, [2005] (Box 27)
    - Weathers Permitting, 1999-2005; 7 (Box 27)
    - Worksheets, undated; 4 (Box 27)
  - Other Papers
    - Reviews, bibliographies, and ephemera relating to Stephen Sandy, 1985-1992, undated (Box 28)
    - Leland Hayward outlines, circa 1966-1967 (Box 28)
- October 2006 Acquisition, 1987-1997; 9; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 29-30 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The October 2006 Acquisition consists of videocassettes of and relating to Stephen Sandy, including videos of poetry readings.
  - "Creeley at Harvard Summer School", undated; YCALMSS744_0001; 1; 02:04:08 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102300317)
    This is a series of "Saturday Night Live" episodes on this tape.
  - "Stephen Sandy reading, Bennington Free Library", 1997 April 17; YCALMSS744_0002; 1; 00:55:39 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102300325)
    audio and video recordings:Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - "Bob Creeley at Harvard Summer School", 1987; YCALMSS744_0003; 1; 00:05:24 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102370351)
  - "Bronkville Poetry Club: Stephen Sandy", undated; YCALMSS744_0004; 1; 01:17:11 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102417855)
  - "Stephen Sandy at the Kitty Factory, New York City", 1989 June 13; YCALMSS744_0005; 1; 01:10:21 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102417863)
  - "Reading at Suffolk University", 1993 October; YCALMSS744_0006; 1; 00:52:33 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102417871)
- May 2008 Acquisition, 1992-2007; 10; 0.21; (1 box)
  The May 2008 Acquisition consists of material removed from books acquired from Stephen Sandy, including writings and correspondence.
  - Book reviews, 1994, 2007 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence
    - Daniel, David, undated (Box 31)
    - Martin, Charles, 1995 (Box 31)
    - Miller, Joel B., undated (Box 31)
  - "Around Our Table", 1992 (Box 31)
- June 2008 Acquisition, 1957-2007; 11; 1.5; (3 boxes)
  Organized under three headings: Journals, Correspondence, and Other Papers.
  The June 2008 Acquisition consists of the journals of Stephen Sandy, correspondence, and photographs. Journals include personal reflections, notes toward drafts of writings, poems in various draft versions, and financial notes. Correspondence consists chiefly of professional and personal letters from writers and literary organizations, documenting the literary community in which Sandy is active. Other subject files consist of material relating to a particular person or topic (e.g. Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation). Other Papers include photographs of Stephen Sandy at Bennington College and with his daughter.
  - Journals
    Arranged numerically. Numbers were assigned prior to acquisition by the library.
    - Journal #1 (Cambridge, Minneapolis), 1957-1961 (Box 32)
    - Journal #2 (Paris), 1961 (Box 32)
    - Journal #3 (California, Mexico, Yaddo), 1962-1963 (Box 32)
    - Journal #4 (Martha's Vineyard, Providence), 1966-1968 (Box 32)
    - Journal #5 (Bennington), 1980-1983 (Box 32)
    - Journal #6 (Vermont), 1980-1984 (Box 32)
    - Journal #7 (Vermont), 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Journal #8 (Blue Mountain Center), 1988 (Box 32)
    - Journal #9 (MacDowell Colony, Vermont, Chicago, Colorado, Yale, Yaddo, Davidson College), 1993-1994 (Box 32)
    - Journal #10 (Italy), 2001 (Box 32)
    - Journal #11 (Italy), 2001-2003 (Box 32)
    - Journal #12 (Vermont), 1987 (Box 32)
    - Journal #13 (New York, Vermont), 1975 (Box 32)
    - Journal #14 (New York, Vermont), 1976 (Box 32)
    - Journal #15 (New York, Vermont), 1978-1979 (Box 32)
    - Journal #16 (Vermont, Davidson College), 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence
    - Academy of American Poets and Liam Rector, 2005-2007, undated (Box 32)
    - Adams, Pat, 2005 (Box 32)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1990-2007 (Box 32)
    - Barnet, Peter, 2006-2007 (Box 32)
    - Barnstone, Willis, 1992-1993 (Box 32)
    - Barr, John W., 2007-2008 (Box 32)
    - Bate, Walter Jackson, 1983 September 26 (Box 32)
    - Beck, Rosemarie, 1997-1998 (Box 32)
    - Calleo, David P., 1992-2002 (Box 32)
    - Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation Annual Dinner, 2003 (Box 32)
    - Coble, Gerald, 1987-2003, undated (Box 32)
    - Cooley, Martha, 2007 (Box 32)
    - Corbett, William, 2003, undated (Box 32)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Cramer, Steven, 1996, undated (Box 32)
    - Creeley, Robert, 2003 December 1 (Box 32)
    - Del Tredici, David, 1999-2001 (Box 33)
    - Felstiner, John, 2002, undated (Box 33)
    - Franklin, Cornell S., 1998, undated (Box 33)
    - Franzen, Jonathan, 1993-2005 (Box 33)
    - Freas, Donald Arthur, 1996, undated (Box 33)
    - Gurganus, Allan, 1994-2007, undated (Box 33)
    - Hall, Donald, 2001-2007 (Box 33)
    - Holland, Gill, 1998-2003 (Box 33)
    - Takano, Masao, 2006-2007, undated (Box 33)
    - Tokunaga, Shozo, 1998-2006, undated (Box 33)
    - Vivante, Arturo, 2002-2005 (Box 33)
  - Other Papers
    - Photographs, 1977-1988, undated; 3 (Box 33)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 34)
    - "One Section from Revolutions", 1973 August (Box 34)
- June 2009 Acquisition, 1925-2009; 12; 5.33; (7 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Organized under five headings: Correspondence and Subject Files, Journals, Photographs and Other Papers, Bennington College Material, and Posters and Broadsides.
  The June 2009 Acquisition consists of the journals of Stephen Sandy, correspondence, printed material including posters and broadsides, and photographs. Journals include both personal reflections and notes toward drafts of writings. Correspondence consists chiefly of professional and personal letters from writers and literary organizations, documenting the literary community in which Sandy is active. Other subject files consist of material relating to a particular person or topic (e.g. Relinquishment, Bennington College Retirement). Other Papers include personal photographs of Stephen Sandy, friends, family members, and colleagues, and personal papers including diplomas.
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Aaron, Jonathan, 2007-2008 (Box 35)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1993-2002 (Box 35)
    - Agni, 1999-2007 (Box 35)
    - Aldrich, Alex, 2006-2008, undated (Box 35)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 2006-2007, undated; 2 (Box 35)
    - Ammons, A. R., 1998 (Box 35)
    - Amory, Rob, 2007-2008 (Box 35)
    - Anti-War Readings, Vermont, 2003 (Box 35)
    - Asekoff, Lou, 2005 (Box 35)
    - Ashbery, John, 1985-2009 (Box 35)
    - Ausable Press, 2006-2007 (Box 35)
    - Bach, Steven, 2002 (Box 35)
    - Bagg, Robert, 2007-2008, undated (Box 35)
    - Barr, John, 2003-2009, undated (Box 35)
    - Bellagio, 2003-2006 (Box 35)
      Includes letters from Sheldon and Harriet Segal
    - Bernard, April, 2005 (Box 35)
    - Better Bennington June Arts, 2005 (Box 35)
    - Blue Mountain Center, 2006, undated (Box 35)
    - Bly, Robert, 2004-2005 (Box 35)
    - Boal, Ian, 2006-2007 (Box 35)
    - Boepple, Willard and Maggie, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Brant, Henry, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Brooke, Nick, 2002-2009, undated (Box 35)
    - Brookhouse, Christopher, 2003-2005, undated (Box 35)
    - Budbill, David, 2007-2008, undated (Box 35)
    - Buechner, Fred, 2005-2007, undated (Box 35)
    - Burkhardt, Fred and Anne, 2072-2007 (Box 35)
    - Busch, Aki, 2006-2008, undated (Box 35)
    - Butler, Blaine, 2003-2009 (Box 35)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 2008, undated (Box 35)
    - Charon, Rita, 2004-2007 (Box 35)
    - Cheever, John, 2005 (Box 35)
    - Cole, Henri, 2004 September 14 (Box 35)
    - Coleman, Liz, 1987-2003, undated (Box 35)
    - Creeley, Robert, circa mid-1990s (Box 35)
    - Cumming, Douglas, 2006-2008 (Box 35)
    - Curzon, David, 2006-2007 (Box 35)
    - Davis, Kathryn and Eric Zencey, 2002-2003 (Box 35)
    - Davis-Goff, Annabel, undated (Box 35)
    - Delanty, Greg, 2007, undated (Box 35)
    - Delbanco, Nick, 1979-2006 (Box 35)
    - DeNiord, Chard, 2005-2008, undated; 2 (Box 35)
    - Dennis, Carl, 2004-2007 (Box 35)
    - Denver Quarterly, 2002-2008 (Box 35)
    - Desai, Kiran, 1991-2006 (Box 35)
    - Dickerson, George, 2008-2009 (Box 36)
    - Easterly, John, 2001-2006 (Box 36)
    - Edwards, Harvey, 2006 (Box 36)
    - Ehrlich, Gretel, 2002-2005 (Box 36)
    - Elman, Richard, 1986 July (Box 36)
    - The Epoch, 1990, undated (Box 36)
    - Feinman, Alvin, 2008 (Box 36)
    - Foster, Tom, 2002-2004, undated (Box 36)
    - Fredericks, Claude, 1958 (Box 36)
    - Gale Thomson, 2006 March 7 (Box 36)
    - Garrett, George, 1997-2005 (Box 36)
    - Gelman, Josh, 2003-2008 (Box 36)
    - Gilley, Ted, 2006-2009, undated (Box 36)
    - Global Warming Readings, 2006-2007 (Box 36)
    - Goldstein, Larry, 2006-2009 (Box 36)
    - Gowrie, Grey, Earl of, 2002-2009, undated (Box 36)
    - Hadas, Rachel, 2001-2009 (Box 36)
    - Hagen, Daron, 2002 May 28 (Box 36)
    - Harrison, Jeffrey, 2008 (Box 36)
    - Harvard Review, 2005-2006 (Box 36)
    - Hass, Robert, 1993 March 8 (Box 36)
    - Hayes, Mary, 2004-2005 (Box 36)
    - Heaney, Seamus, 1990-2006 (Box 36)
    - Hoagland, Edward, 1990-2009 (Box 36)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1991-1999 (Box 36)
    - Howard, Richard, 2001-2009 (Box 36)
    - Imlah, Mick, 2004-2007, undated (Box 36)
    - Isherwood, John, 2007, undated (Box 36)
    - Kennedy, X. J., 2007-2008 (Box 36)
    - Kenyon, Jane, 1995 April 26 (Box 36)
    - Kirchwey, Karl, 1992, 2000 (Box 36)
    - Klitzman, Robert, 2002, undated (Box 36)
    - Krementz, Jill, 2007 (Box 36)
    - Kuzma, Steve, 2004-2008 (Box 36)
    - Lanyon, Ellen, 1976-2008 (Box 36)
    - Latuchie, Karen, [no year] May 26 (Box 36)
    - Leibowitz, Herb, 2001-2003, undated (Box 36)
    - Lethem, Jonathan, 2003-2007 (Box 36)
    - Levine, Jeffrey, 2007 (Box 36)
    - Lindley, David and Lucia Woods, 2006-2007 (Box 36)
    - Louisiana State University Press, 1996-2002 (Box 36)
    - Lovell, Ellen McCulloch, 2004 (Box 36)
    - MacDowell Colony, 1995 January 25 (Box 36)
    - Mackenzie, Warren, 2007-2008 (Box 36)
    - Magowan, Robin and Juliet, 2003-2007, undated (Box 36)
    - Maguire, Gregory, 2004-2008 (Box 36)
    - Malamud, Bernard, 1983-2003, undated (Box 36)
    - Maris, Kathryn, 2006-2008 (Box 36)
    - Martin, Charles, 2002, undated (Box 36)
    - Mason, Jerry, 2000-2005 (Box 36)
    - Merrill, James, 1918-1992, undated (Box 36)
    - Miller, Chris, 2002-2009 (Box 36)
    - Miller, David, 1990, 2009 (Box 36)
    - Mitten, David, 2002-2005 (Box 36)
    - Morrison, Micah, 2005-2006 (Box 36)
    - Movius, Geoffrey and John, 2003-2006 (Box 36)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1973-2003; 2 (Box 36)
    - Netsuke Days, 2008, undated (Box 36)
    - Northshire Bookstore, 1992-2004 (Box 36)
    - Nurkse, Dennis, 2002-2004 (Box 36)
    - O'Brien, Geoffrey, 2003, undated (Box 36)
    - Okrent, Becky, 2003-2005 (Box 36)
    - Pape, Greg, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Pettingell, Phoebe, 2006-2007 (Box 36)
    - Porter, David, 2006-2007 (Box 36)
    - Randall, Julia, 1975-2006, undated (Box 36)
    - Rauniyar, Ravi K., 2002-2003, undated (Box 36)
    - The Reader, 2008 (Box 36)
    - Reed, Mark, 1995-2007 (Box 36)
    - Reeve, Frank and Laura R., 2005-2008, undated (Box 36)
    - Relinquishment, Bennington College Retirement, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Resch, Tyler, 2007-2008 (Box 37)
    - Romer, Chris, 2002-2007, undated (Box 37)
    - Ruefle, Mary, 2006-2007, undated (Box 37)
    - Salamander, 2002-2003 (Box 37)
    - Sandy, Alan, 2006-2008 (Box 37)
    - Saul, Harry, 2008 (Box 37)
    - Schley, Jim, 2004-2008 (Box 37)
    - Scully, James, 2007-2008 (Box 37)
    - Slavitt, David, 2007-2009 (Box 37)
    - Souter, David H., 2006 March 7 (Box 37)
    - Southern Review, 2002-2008 (Box 37)
    - St. Armand, Barton, 2007-2008 (Box 37)
    - Surface Impressions, 1997-2002 (Box 37)
    - Swann Auction Galleries, 2006 (Box 37)
    - Takano, Masao, 1968-2007 (Box 37)
    - Taylor, Henry, 2002-2004 (Box 37)
    - Towle, Parker, 2002-2009 (Box 37)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1998 (Box 37)
    - Vermont Arts Council, 1999-2008 (Box 37)
    - Vermont Life, 2007 December 12 (Box 37)
    - Vermont Review of Books, 2005 (Box 37)
    - Verter, Brad, 2003-2006 (Box 37)
    - Vivante, Arturo, 2006-2007 (Box 37)
    - Voigt, Ellen, 2003-2009 (Box 37)
    - Wadsworth, Bill, 2002-2003 (Box 37)
    - Wallace, Tom, 1988-2003 (Box 37)
    - Waxwings, 2004 December (Box 37)
    - Westchester Poetry Conference, 2007 (Box 37)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 2005-2008 (Box 37)
    - Wilner, Eleanor, 2005 August 31 (Box 37)
    - Wunderlich, Mark, 2004-2005 (Box 37)
    - Wylie, Andrew, 1967 February 11 (Box 37)
    - Yaddo, 2002-2006; 3 (Box 37)
    - Bits of Publicity, 1994-1995 (Box 37)
    - Broadsides, 1982-2006 (Box 37)
    - Family, 1972-2007 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous & reviews, 1989-2008 (Box 37)
    - Readings, 1988 Fall (Box 37)
    - Tokyo, 1967 (Box 37)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1986-2008; 3 (Box 37)
  - Journals
    Arranged roughly chronologically.
    Description and numbering of journals based on information supplied with the collection. No descriptions were provided for B37 and B38.
    - B1. Cambridge. Ex-US. Army, 1957-1958 (Box 38)
    - B2. Cambridge. Dunster. Drug experiments, 1961-1962 (Box 38)
    - B3. Harvard. "V." Lionel, Yaddo, 1963-1965 (Box 38)
    - B4. "IV." Yaddo. Austin Warren dialogs. Fiction notes ("Good Time War"). Virgil Thompson, etc., 1963-1964 (Box 38)
    - B5. Harvard. Grays Hall. AW death., 1964-1965 (Box 38)
    - B6. Cambridge, 1964-1966 (Box 38)
    - B7. "VII." Brimfield, Yaddo, Cambridge, 1966 July - August (Box 38)
    - B8. Providence. Brown strike / protests. Draft poems. Inventories. Teaching., 1968 (Box 38)
    - B9. Japan (Tokyo, Oshima, Imaihama, Sapporo), 1968 (Box 38)
    - B10. Japan (Tokyo, Sendai, Kanazawa, Niigata), 1968 (Box 38)
    - B11.Tokyo, Todai — U.S., Brown, 1968 (Box 38)
    - B12. Cambridge '68 - Bennington '69 - '71. Miscellany. Arts & Crafts project., 1968-1971 (Box 38)
    - B13. Bennington & Tokyo. (Fire & Rehire), 1969-1971 (Box 38)
    - B14. Bennington (Shingle Cottage), Japan (Tokyo: Tom Hall res., Totsuka). Early drafts poems in Roofs (Japan), 1970-1972 (Box 38)
    - B15. Japan. Tokyo. Drafts / notes for poems., early 1970s (Box 38)
    - B16. Bennington; White Creek. Drafts of poems., 1972-1973 (Box 38)
    - B17. Tokyo, (Tutsuka), 1972 (Box 38)
    - B18. California; "Sebastopol Log". 1). Cross-country bus (via mpls). 2). House sit for Bro. AFS. 3) sights in California, 1973 July (Box 38)
    - B19. White Creek, Eagle Bridge NY. More Calif, house sit AFS Sebastopol. Long Beach, visit Aunt Irene, notes of her talk., 1974-1975 (Box 38)
    - B20. Bennington Coll. notes & quotes, mostly A. Feinman, as to Camille & Harold Bloom (+ Camille Paglia lecture), 1977-1978 (Box 38)
    - B21. Bennington College. Orchard C. (Melissa Greene on Nick Delbanco Stephen Dunn on Ashbery, etc.) Drafts of poems, e.g., "Pen Doom.", 1983-1984 (Box 38)
    - B22. Bennington College. Quotes & notes, 1984 (Box 38)
    - B23. "So Good So Far.", 1991 (Box 38)
    - B24. "Bennington College." Student, Healey, o.d. death. Andre Bernold & J. Barr (Chmn Board)., 1992 (Box 38)
    - B26. Davidson College and Dreams, NC., 1994 (Box 38)
    - B27. Clare's graduation. Frank Bidart, Mark Edmundson, etc., 1994-1995 (Box 38)
    - B28. Bennington Coll. Clare; Nat. Clare at Brown, take & fetch. Orig/early drafts "Mother's Day" (Atlantic), other poems ("productive" yr). Family & college. Annisquam, Moviuses. Student Matt Gross shot in massacre atop Empire State., 1996-1997 (Box 38)
    - B29. College. Yaddo. Drafts poems for Black Box. "Pastel Evidence; "Wednesday," "Detention Period," "Home Movie" etc.Full orig text Diva. College, R Hadas for reading. Arthur Danto @ Benn. Good yr for poem sketches, 1996-1998 (Box 39)
    - B30. Bennington / Weathers Permitting work. Imp. quotes. Bishop; Eliz Sifton. Clare to Wash. DC. Pooh Randall. Bush epigrams; War. Andre Gide journals. Read & taught New Engl Coll, —deNiord's program; (meet Li Young Lee) on way to see Burriss Young, pancreatic c. in Cambridge; Dwight Miller phones says that BY died (while I taught.), 2001-2007 (Box 39)
    - B30 ½. Bennington College. TNSC = Tuesday Nite Supper Club, faculty to whom SS read. SS resigns from Benn faculty. Family together, porch at 25 West St. Summer MFA (Liam bin Rector); readings, Skidmore. Brimfield. S (sister Susan) nervous; boys there., 2002-2004 (Box 39)
    - B31. "This Day and Age." Yaddo, Aug, 03, Term to come. Ned Rorem. Felstiners, briefly. NYC Sept: Eakins show; Mike & Evie Malinowitz, Star Black, Ashbery, Klitzman. Lunch Humanities Club/Group NYU w/ R Howard. Herb Leibowitz, Ann Hollander, S. Rushdie, chatted abt his staying Dorset near me, Liz Frank, Ted Mooney, Susan Sontag, Liz Frank. Sat w/ Ashbery & chatted on train back, Hudson. A reading Pevear's Dostoevsky Idiot. Ruefle's Musk Ox People., 2002-2003 (Box 39)
    - B31 ½. National Book Awards ceremony, NYU. Yale PBK Poet New Haven trip. Tom Foster. Radiation., 2003-2004 (Box 39)
    - B32. Bennington. NYC, July. Delanty. T Foster. Brimfield: Flea, J&S, John Portola their friend. Visit Peter Davison. 72 River St Bos. Shrunken. Chemo. Carriage Loft. S. Kunitz. Poetry., 2004 (Box 39)
    - B33. Gloucester. NYC. Bennington. Clare & Peter, Chris Miller, Ted Hoagland, Joan Gardner for Thksgiving din. Death Tom Foster, 2002-2005 (Box 39)
    - B34. Reading @ Northshire, no publ. Weathers Permitting publisht. "11.iv.05". Note draft to Annabel Davis-Goff, read Fox's Walk.Scan. Dr. StClair. Retirement aftermath, 2005 January - September (Box 39)
    - B35. Bennington. C Dewey with Tibet stands, one made on lathe; he inquired of Renate Wheelock, Explain tumor not "in" but "at" pancreas; & her surgeries & chemo's. (Seen by Ruth Dewey and Peggy at Alldays w Joan Gardner). This little world journal. Down days. Trip to Burlington, 2006 September (Box 39)
    - B36. Clare's wedding. McCullough garden. Dick Wilbur, Bruce Weber. (This the Wilbur talk on Frost reading at Tishman, Col. for the Frost Stone House Museum Sun 13 Nov.) Accidie. Remarks, dialog Mother Anita., 2005-2006 (Box 39)
    - B37, 2006 (Box 39)
    - B38, 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Bennington College Material
    - Bennington College Trustees Entertaining themselves and Barr as Barr Resigns, A musical, partial script, undated (Box 39)
    - "Hate mail" concerning President Coleman firing faculty at Bennington College, 1994-1995 (Box 39)
      Correspondence, petitions, letters, newspaper clippings concerning Coleman's firing of faculty in 1994
    - Clippings, 1994-2006 (Box 39)
      Concerning Bennington's re-organization, 1994-2006, chiefly New York Times and Bennington Banner
    - The Edward Hoagland Affair, 1991 (Box 39)
      Correspondence, documents, legal pronouncements, concerning the decision by Bennington College to fire Ted Hoagland
    - Coleman, Liz (President of Bennington College, 1987-2009) (Box 39)